CONTACT

Address: Flat Number 5, Elizabeth Place,

High Wycombe, HP12 4AE **Phone**: +44 7448314537

Email: vikas_mullana@yahoo.com

SKILLS

- Integration architecture
- MuleSoft 4.x
- Cloudhub 1.0 and 2.0
- RAMI
- Rest API, SOAP
- Jenkins
- Dataweave , Java, Python, Typescript,
- Frameworks: Spring, Angular, Struts, JSF, Flask
- ORM: Hibernate
- AWS RDS, DynamoDB, ECS, SNS
- Microservices
- Relational DB: MySQL, Oracle DB
- Non-Relational DB Amazon DynamoDB
- Cache Redis In-memory DB
- HTML 5, CSS 3
- Cucumber, Rest-Assured
- JMeter
- Maven
- Git, SVN
- Jira, Rally
- Tableau, PowerBI

BLOGS

- Dashboards <u>Link</u>
- Behavioural Headers <u>Link</u>
- Streaming strategy <u>Link</u>

CERTIFICATIONS

- MuleSoft Certified Integration Architect
- MuleSoft Certified Platform Architect
- MuleSoft Certified Developer
- Oracle Certified Java Pofessional
- Google Associate Cloud Engineer
- Google Certified TensorFlow Developer

Vikas Puri

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Vikas has 12 plus years of enriched experience in IT industry. He has worked on various skills such as Integration Architecture and Development, Full-Stack development and Dev-Ops. He is MuleSoft Certified Integration Architect, Platform Architect and Developer. He also presented his knowledge on "Einstein API" as the MuleSoft Meetup Speaker. Vikas also wrote MuleSoft blogs on Behavioural Headers, Solace Integration, Streaming strategies, and API Insight dashboard. Vikas provided the innovative idea which solved MuleSoft customer problem and designed dashboards in Tableau. Apart from Integration and Full stack development, Vikas is also having good interest in Artificial Intelligence, and is also Google Certified TensorFlow Developer. In addition to this, Vikas is always keen to learn new things and certified Google Cloud Associate, Boomi Associate and Professional Developer. Vikas also worked on GenAI and developed Video analytics tool.

WORK HISTORY

Integration Architect

02/2022 - Present

Deloitte - London, United Kingdom

Agency Model Implementation, allowing automotive company to sell cars as a retailer. Implementation of the new sales and marketing CRM system with the aim of streamlining business processes in line with their improvements to the customer journey to have customer 360 view, using MuleSoft as the technology to integrate between Salesforce and different internal/external systems.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- 1. Integration Architecture design
- 2. Lead a team of 5 members and delivered the project on time.
- 3. Purposed solution to the client saving their 20-30k \$/year, and also making the application perform well.
- 4. Purposed solution to the client with which they can monitor and have high level overview of resources which can lead to optimise utilise the resources.
- 5. Involved in doing coding for complex integrations and helping team to sort the technical challenges.
- 6. Involved in doing code review, and responsible for delivering the product with good quality of code.
- 7. Closely engaged with the client in understanding the business and providing them the technical solutions.
- 8. Setup the Jenkins Pipelines

Integration Architect

Deloitte - London, United Kingdom

Initiative taken by me which helps client to have bird eye view of the MuleSoft resources, its unnecessary utilisation which is resulting to license cost and other security prospects. Also published the article about the same which can be found by

Roles and Responsibilities:

- 1. Designed the architecture and developed the MuleSoft code for the same
- 2. Helped Tableau resource in designing the dashboards.

Python Developer

Deloitte - London, United Kingdom

Worked as Python Developer to perform POC on the video analytics tool.

- Designed high level architecture of the application.
- Designed and developing application to upload videos to Google Cloud.
- Develop GenAl application to perform video analysis (like we can ask summary, genre and other details) of the uploaded video.

Tech Stack: Python 3.12, Flask, Angular 18, Google Cloud - Object Storage, Google Compute Engine.

Associate Lead

07/2014 - 12/2019

Nagarro Software Pvt. Ltd. - Gurugram, India

Worked as Associate Lead for the Top most Automobile company in Germany.

- Participated in deciding the technical approaches.
- Involved in the requirement gathering and doing the POC for the same.
- Involved in the coding of front end using Angular 4, HTML 5 and CSS 3.
- Involved in the coding of backend using Java, Hibernate, Spring.
- Involved in developing the Jenkins pipeline.
- Actively involved in the code reviews.
- Introduced the Flyway for maintaining the database of different environments in sync.
- Introduced caching using Redis.
- Implemented Stored Procedures, Triggers and views.

IT Engineer - SI

05/2012 - 06/2014

CMC Limited - Noida, India

Worked as IT engineer for the product of one the Indian Consulting services.

- Prepared high level design documents like ER diagrams, Sequence Diagrams.
- Involved in the development of the application using Java, JSF and Primefaces.
- Involved in writing the queries and stored procedures.
- Involved in improving the performance of the gueries.
- Introduced the JMS, so as soon as request raised other systems will be notified.

Software Engineer

10/2010 - 04/2012

NTT Data - Noida, India

Worked as Software Engineer for Leading Hospital chain in the US.

- Involved in the development of the backend code using Java, and Struts.
- Involved in writing the DB Stored Procedures.
- Involved in fixing the bugs.

EDUCATION

Master's in Artificial Intelligence and Robotics: Jan 2020 - Jan 2022, University of Hertfordshire - Hatfield, Hertfordshire, England

Bachelor of Technology: Electronic and Instrumentation Engineering, 06/2008 **Maharishi Markandeshwar Engineering College** - Mullana, Haryana, India